Guide to the New York State Council on the Arts Electronic Media and Film Program records, [ca. 1960-2011]
New York State Council on the Arts Electronic Media and Film Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Council on the Arts Electronic Media and Film Program records, [ca. 1960-2011]
8230
New York State Council on the Arts.
19 cubic feet.
Digital media, Publications, Printed materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records from the Electronic Media and Film Program (EMF) and the Individual Artists Program (IND) include media field reports and surveys, files on organizations and individual artists, support for production, distributions, and organization, special projects files, film festival catalogs, Set in Motion records, books, reports, and other publications. Also includes media materials such as video, film, tape recordings, photographs, as well as digital files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Electronic Media and Film (EMF) Program is dedicated to furthering artistic growth and public engagement in the media arts. EMF supports a variety of activities enabling diverse constituents to participate in the development, exhibition and appreciation of film and electronic media, including moving image, sound, and technology as an art form. To ensure diversity within the media arts, EMF welcomes and supports a range of non-profit organizations including technology centers, independent cinemas, museums, galleries and broadcasters as well as internet-based dissemination. EMF has a long-standing commitment to creative exploration and exhibition in all aspects of the media arts, including film and media appreciation, professional development, technology and new modes of exhibition, distribution and interdisciplinary work.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records from the Electronic Media and Film Program (EMF) and the Individual Artists Program (IND) include media field reports and surveys, files on organizations and individual artists, support for production, distributions, and organization, special projects files, film festival catalogs, Set in Motion records, books, reports, and other publications. Also includes media materials such as video, film, tape recordings, photographs, as well as digital files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Council on the Arts.
Subjects:
Art -- New York (State); Artists -- New York (State); Composers -- New York (State); Computer art -- New York (State); Documentary films -- New York (State); Experimental films -- New York (State); Film festivals.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Video recordings; Tape recordings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of the Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art.
SERIES LIST
Administrative Files
Box 1-6
General
Set in Motion - Artists Files
Electronic Media and Film Program: Grant Applicants and Award Winners 2002-2003
Series II. Organizations A-Z
Boxes 7-9
A-M
N-POI
POR-W
Series III. Individuals A-Z
Box 9-14
A-C
D-F
G-I
J-M
N-R
S-Z
Series IV. Reports and Catalogs
Box 15
Series IV. Film Festival and Film Series Brochures and Schedules
Box 16-17
Series V. Media
Box 18-19
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Administrative Files
  - General
    - Radio Roundtable 1997 - Fostering the Independent Spirit, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, press releases, memos, registration forms, newspaper clippings, list of contacts, sign in sheet, report and follow-up correspondence
    - New Applicants - 2001, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Memo, correspondence (emails) brochure for the Woodstock Film Festival with news clippings and press releases
    - Correspondence, press releases, meeting notices, reports, mailing lists, sign-in sheets, on-line survey summery, 1993-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Television/Media - 1978-1979, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Meeting notes, mission statement, correspondence, memos, agenda items, correspondence, press release
    - Media Panel, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, Memos, meeting notes
    - Media - Allocation, Policy, End Year Reports (Historic), 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, memos, abstracts, meeting notes, allocation
    - Libraries (?), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Allocation paper, survey reports, memos, statement regarding contemporary performance work
    - Film Program Evaluation Panel, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, handwritten notes, list of films, programs for children and teens; STANLEY KUBRICK
    - Advisory meetings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      meeting notes, handwritten notes, address lists, correspondence
    - Radio Information Compilation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Correspondence, program policies and objectives from WNPE
    - Media Panel 1978-1979, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      memos, correspondence, panel recommendations
    - Return to Archive, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Of the Artist, by the Artists, for the People: The Creative Artists Public Service Program
    - Past Correspondence, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Festivals, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Study guide for Hard Days Night, programs (including an Italian film festival at UCLA in 1963), news clippings
    - Film Projects - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Correspondence, film program proposal (marked confidential), job description for film program director
    - Film Study Courses - Mailing lists, 1958-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Programs and schedules for film series
    - Mailing lists and meeting notes, 1966-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      memos, master list of recipient organizations and individual artists, Set in Motion materials, TV/Media program costs, public television memo, meeting notes with the Motion Picture Association of America, contact sheet of photographs
    - Copies from archive, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      All photocopies: materials about cable, video art, Action Theatre: The Happenings of Ken Dewey exhibition catalog, meeting notes, TV/Media Panel agenda
    - State Film Project: State of the Art, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Project budget materials; mailing list; Claudia Weill correspondence and issue of The Big Reel featuring Girlfriends with Melanie Mayron and Christopher Guest
    - New York Film Festival - 1965, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Flier, program, press pass, press release, clipping
    - Statistics, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      memos and funding forms of support
    - National Endowments for the Arts - Misc., 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Grant materials, correspondence, Cornell University
    - Proposal for Alternatives in Art, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Bronx Council on the Arts
    - Film Bureau, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Fliers for films, correspondence, program for the super 8 film festival in Paris
    - Film Teaching, 1965-1969, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      study and teaching guides, questionnaires, survey results, mailing lists, National Center for Film Study materials
    - Fordham Film Conference, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      meeting notes, correspondence, event schedule
    - American Film Institute, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Correspondence, press release, preliminary rescue list, archives program
    - Dartmouth Conference, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      schedule, correspondence, film cataloging information from the Library of Congress, handwritten notes
    - The Museum of Modern Art Film and Video Exhibition Program Report, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - New Community Cinema Publicity Materials, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Fliers, Film-Arts-In-Education materials, newspaper clippings, community support letters
    - Electronic Arts Intermix Publicity Materials, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      EAI collection, new artists, new tapes, special programs, catalogue publications, new media
    - Experimental Television Center Publicity Materials, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Radio Round Table, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Black/Latino/People of Color Programming Samples, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      newspaper clippings, film and conference programs
    - Minority Exhibition/Conference, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      handwritten notes, newsletters, film and conference programs, memos, correspondence, (Do the Right Thing conference)
    - National Alliance for Media Arts and Culture Conference Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      conference papers, proposals, copies of articles
    - Public Television Production Fund (Early Initiatives), 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      reports, correspondence, proposals for The National Independent Program Service, memos, copies of articles,
    - Production/ October Meeting (FY1987), 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      reports and proposals on independent production, meeting notes, statement from the chairman, subcommittee on telecommunications and finance, memos, correspondence, handwritten notes,copies of articles, press releases, mailing list (Altermedia - background APF)
    - Dance Theater Workshop, Inc. - Background, 1990-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, statements, and program proposals related to the Dance Theater Workshop, also materials related to a new theater at Carnegie Hall and the American Multiracial film series
    - Dance Theater Workshop, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, programs, schedules, press releases, copies of articles, fliers
    - Cinema Annex, Inc.(NYS: FY1996:8337), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      NYSERNet materials
    - Cathedral St. John the Divine: Cathedral Arts (91-9973), 1990-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      memos, programs and schedules, seating plan, exhibition regrant, copy of article
    - Cayuga County Arts Council, Inc.(NYS: 001231 FY1995:4546), 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Correspondence, fliers, schedule of events
    - Center for Cuban Studies, Inc. (FY94-2521), 1987-1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, catalogue, publicity materials
    - Cable Television in American Education: A Buffalo Affair, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      conference materials
    - Non-Return Applicant Surveys and National Endowment for the Arts and Technical Assistance Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      copies of handwritten notes regarding Policy Panel, materials relating to the New York Media Arts Technical Assistance Fund
    - Independent Production Funds, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      memos, correspondence, promotional materials, reports
    - Film Production FY96, 1985-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
      list of NYFA Artist' Fellowships recipients 1985-1993, How IND Works, Independent Artists Program application
    - Early Film Reports, 1982-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
      list of film production award recipients, 1975-1980, productions lists, lists of films funded, Film Co-Production Award Follow-Up Survey
    - 82-83 Robert Gardner King James Version (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Also includes material on Ken Burns' film about the Brooklyn Bridge
    - Jill Godmilow, and Ethel Raim - Albanians in the Bronx, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Correspondence, grant materials, copy of Serbian newspaper, change of grant monies to Chronicle of a String Quartet
    - 83-84 Jill Godmilow - Far From Poland, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      publicity materials for the film - cast, synopsis, fliers
    - 81-82 Charles Ahearn - Wild Style, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      grand application materials, press materials, copy of newspaper clipping
    - 81-82 Joanne Akalaitis - Dead End Kids, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Note: Music score by David Byrne with additional music by Philip Glass. Grant application materials, press materials, newspaper clippings, correspondence
    - 79-80 Scott and Beth B. - Vortex, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      follow-up survey, publicity materials, contact information
    - Perrin Ireland and Mirra Bank - Spirit to Spirit, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Correspondence, publicity materials, resume for Terry Galloway
    - 77-78 Mirra Bank and Ellen Hovdes - Ordinary Lives, 1984 undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Correspondence, follow-up, screenplay for Enormous changes at the Last Minute by John Sayles
    - Film Co-Production Report, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      co-production follow-up survey, information about contracts with artists, meeting notes about awards, list of award winners from 1982-1985
    - Set in Motion - FSLC Press, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      memos, out-line and list pf films for publicity around NYSCAs Set in Motion series
    - NYSCA Production by Year, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Box lists from Youth Film Archive, catalog for Movies from Youth Film Distribution Center
    - Alan Berliner - The Family Album, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      list of screenings, fliers, copies of newspaper clippings, transcript of an NPR report
    - 79-80 Mikhail Bogin - A Private Life, c.1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Final report form, program for screening at the Museum of Modern Art, fliers
    - 86-87 Stephanie Black - The Hands that Feed Us, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Project specs, correspondence, award letter
    - 78-79 Carl Clay - Respect, c. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      follow-up questionnaire, press materials for Black Spectrum Theater Co.
    - 81-82 Fred Cohen - Players of the D'Aquisto Guitar, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Film entitled The New Yorker Special; fliers, application, copies of news clippings, crew list
    - 86-87 Pamela Cohen - Maria's Story, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      publicity materials, follow-up, copies of newspaper clippings, theater programs
    - 79-80 Kathy Collins - Cruz Brothers and Miss Malloy, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
      an interview with Kathleen Collins, fliers
    - Joseph J. Friedman and H. Jay Manis (NEA Bi-Cen) - Earthworks, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Project proposal, correspondence
    - Hilary Harris (Bi-Cen) - Exchange, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Correspondence, NEA application, NYSCA application,
    - Paul Sharit (Bi-Cen) - Declarative Mode, 1976 undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      NYSCA application, correspondence, film series flier, information on the work of Paul Sharits
    - Jack Ofield (Bi-Cen) - Adirondack Minstrel, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      application materials, correspondence, financial statements, information on the work of Jack Ofield
    - Theodor Timreck (Bi-Cen) - Charles Ives, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      application materials, correspondence, financial statements, fliers, letters of support
    - Roger Murphy S.F.P. (2/77) - Thoroughbred Racing, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      application materials, proposal
    - Tom McDonough (Bi-Cen) - American Comic Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
      proposal
    - Film Production Awards Follow-Up Study Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Lucille Rhodes and Margaret Murphy for Three Women Artists, Kenneth Burns for Brooklyn Bridge, Patricia Jaffe for Ahynung America - Two Korean Families, Mirre Bant and Ellen Houde for Faith in the Afternoon, Dee Dee Halleck for Films by Children: An Anthology, Eric Breitbart for Fatherhood, Leo Hurwitz for Dialoge with a Woman Departed, Sheryll Miller for The South Bronx as Seen Through the Eyes of Children, Nancy Meshkoff for a film about Mary Alice Bill Brand for Split Decision, Charles Musser for The Emergence of Cinema, Kathy Collins for The Cruz Brothers and Mrs. Malloy, Christine Choy To Love, Honor, and Obey, and Anita Thacher for a film about Eastern Long Island
    - RIGA Video Centre, c. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      program
    - Rockefeller Distribution Initiative, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Correspondence, response to Herman Krawitz's video publishing proposal, meeting notes, feasibility study
    - TVM Tape Library, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Video and audio library list
    - Hudson Valley Film and Video Office (NYS: 001231 FY1998: 0090), 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
      press and program materials for the Hudson Valley Film Festival, copies of newspaper clippings
    - (unlabelled) State Arts Organizations, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      memos and correspondence regarding digital media; copies of meeting notes from Alliance of NYS Arts Organizations May-July 1998; Memos regarding the New York State Museum.
    - Various Reports, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      6 reports/papers related to the Rockefeller Foundation/Jerman Krawitz Videocassette Distribution Task Force; Distribution for New York State Artists Survey; Young Artists Development Opportunities for the Black Filmmaker Foundation, NEA State and Regional Program: Arts Projects in Under-Served Communities
    - Distribution Survey Data, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      questionnaire, survey results, list of previous award winners
    - Distribution - NYS Filmmakers FY1986, 1986-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      application materials, lists of previous award winners, correspondence, film panel notes, handwritten notes, questionnaires and survey materials from 1992
    - Distribution - Returns (85), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, application forms, panel comment forms
    - Distributors List as of 1996, 1991 and 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - NYSCA Distribution (FY94), 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Grant guidelines and application materials, list of artists, correspondence with artists, handwritten notes
    - Distribution for New York State Artists (FY1999), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Grant guidelines and application materials, list of artists, correspondence with artists
    - Distribution for New York State Artists (FY2000), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - DIST00 Files, c. 1999; 3.5" Floppy, FD-7 (Box 3)
      In Folder 8
    - Distribution for New York State Artists (FY2001), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Distribution for New York State Artists (FY2002), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Distributor's Lists, 1991, 1996, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      archive lists, box lists, additions to archive, correspondence
    - Video Archive - Visual Studies Workshops, 1991 and 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Video Preservation, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Correspondence on preservation initiatives, guides on preservation best practices, preservation symposium materials and workshop feedback forms,
    - NYSCA - General, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Correspondence, program materials, press releases, press contacts, handwritten notes
    - Film Magazines and catalogs, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      The Independent Film and Video Monthly and Third World Newsreel's 30th Anniversary
    - Artist Mail Lists, 1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
      mailing lists and report, WNET Programs in the NYSCA Video Archive marked "film tour notes"
    - NYSCA Individual Artists and Electronic Media and Film (EMF) Program, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      program information and previous award winners
    - Electronic Media and Film Contact List, 1992 and 1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      list of artists and organizations
    - Film Bureau, 1984-1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      annual reports and film society program
    - Hudson Valley Film and Video Office (NYS: 001231 FY20000: 0090), 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      promotional materials for the Hudson Valley Film Festival
    - Charas, Inc. - Teatro Charas, 1984-1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Flier and programs
    - National Center for Film and Video Preservation (NCFVP), 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      National Alliance for Media Arts and Culture(NAMAC) grant application foe Video Preservation Symposium(1990), preservation information - formats and best practices (1987-1990)
    - Preservation, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      NAMAC application (1990), UCLA Film and Television Archive (1990), correspondence and articles about film and video preservation (1985-1991)
    - NEA Rural grants/NAMAC State Arts Agency (SAA) - General and Radio Roundtable, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      SAA report (1987-1989), Radio Roundtable proposal (1989) NEA grant information (1989), list of NAMAC awardees (1988), Developing Media Arts within your SAA (1989)
    - Archiving, 1983-1991, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      preservation materials (1983-1991), resumes (undated), EMF FY2006 DGR1 - Agenda (2005)
    - Video Archive Record, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Report of the 1991 Survey of Video collections conducted by the Media Alliance and the New York State Council on the Arts, correspondence (1990), Sound Art/Radio (1987), list of films (undated)
    - Video Proposal/ Media Alliance Network, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      NEH grant materials (1994-1995), Getty grant material (1994), Audiovisual Cataloging email (1996)
    - NYSCA Archive - In-house, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
      IND tape library lists
    - Film and Video Distribution - Policy, Meetings, Initiatives, Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      NYSCA meeting summery (1988), Distribution in the 90s, Non-theatrical Distribution of Independent Film and Video (1989), Interviews with New York State Public Library Film Administrators (undated)
    - Film Bureau - Paid (1971-1972), 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Correspondence marked paid
    - Film Bureau Rentals - Paid, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      payment vouchers
    - Film Bureau Rentals - Paid, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      payment vouchers, Film Speakers Bureau list (1974)
    - Film Bureau Rentals - Paid, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      payment vouchers, Film Speakers Bureau list (1975)
    - New York Foundation for the Arts (NYFA) Forms/Film Bureau (1975-1976), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      assignment forms and correspondence regarding appearances (1975-1976), payment vouchers (1975-1976)
    - New York Foundation for the Arts (NYFA) Forms/Film Bureau (1976-1977), 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      assignment forms and correspondence regarding appearances (1976-1977)
    - NYSCA - Reviews, Forms and Report, 1978, 1991, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      In Dire Straits report (1993), EMF program forms (1990, FY1992, 1993), Media Center Reviews (1978)
    - Cinebox - Resource (Community Exhibition Workshop), 1989-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Community Exhibition Workshop, Corning, NY (1991)
    - Exhibition Regrant (FY1996, EMF), 1994, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      forms and correspondence (1994, 1996)
    - Media Action Project, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Preliminary Findings and Recommendations (1987)
    - Ruby Rich, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      Radio related events and papers - Radio Roundtable (1990)
    - (unlabelled folder) - Media Program, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Regional Summery, Media Program profile (1982, 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1986-1987), copies of film articles from the 1960s and 1970s
    - Ruby Rich - Policy papers (1982-1986), 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Allocation and Policy papers (1982-1988), Towards Cultural Democracy development of a multi-cultural arts policy report (1988)
    - New York Network Aeries Carousel, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Correspondence regarding the series, copies of newspaper clippings, ratings (list of artists includes Yoko Ono)
    - Preservation - Collections, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      list of titles held by collections: Asian American Media, Everson Museum of Art, Museo Del Barrio, Port Washington Library; article about Eigenwelt der Apparatewelt; Inside Bedford Stuyvesant; EMF memos and reports,
    - Moving Image Archive - Discussion Group, 1985, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      mailing lists, keynote speech from the Media Alliance Annual Convention 1985, articles, notes and programs dedicated to film/video preservation
    - Moving Image Archive - Discussion Group, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      contact lists, Characteristics of a Universal Storage Medium